All my friends and welcome to exercise number 55, we are asked to the function that rotate and link
at length.
So how to rotate a link, at least consider a link at least that contains numbers one, two, three,
four and five.
We rotate a linked list by changing rotate clockwise, by changing the last one and the last note to
put it at the first one.
This is rotating a link, at least by one degree or one time.
If I need to rotate this link at least two times, so I.
But again, that last element to the first of so I have rotated the original link at least two degrees
or two times.
OK, this is the basics of rotation.
Now how to implement a method or how to create a method that make this a rotation.
We start here by creating creating public void to rotate linked players.
And it took and K as part of me to the function assumes.
This function is rotates a link at least counterclockwise or clockwise, and updates to had the function
assumed that K is smaller than the size of the linked list.
It does not modify the list if K is greater than or equal to the size.
OK, so we check for that.
If K equal equal to zero.
And by the way, we have lectured this in the lecture, so go back to the lectures in order to learn
more about tradition of building this in c we had we have written and see now the first step is
like rotating.
We will either point to Ghaith or null after that loop, so we start by rotating non current equal to
hat.
So the note?
Current reports have had that current will either point to the case or that now after that finishing
the do so end count equal to one, we would create that four count while count less then.
OK supports why count less than one?
Okay.
And current, that's not equal to none.
Then we need to put current equal to current the next and count plus a plus.
OK.
This is how we check for their Lou and we start coding.
Start rotating.
If the current is null, then K is greater than or equal to count of knots and linked list.
Don't change the list in this case.
So if current current equal equal to null, don't make anything just right there.
OK.
Now, no, Kate, no equal to care, the current points to the case and store it in a valuable case,
not that points to the Note 40 in the order the points to the first one, which is an above example.
OK, so we have seen that the case that we are going to to remove or to rotate and now change the next
year, the case.
While we need to make it wide, the current DOT next does not equal to none.
I know it may be confused sometimes, but it is by practice you would master in equal Tarrant current
dot next.
OK, change the head of last, not the previous head.
OK, so next of their last one is now changed to not the first one.
So purulent dot next equal to hath now that this changed the head.
So again, we need to change the had to k plus one note.
So the head is now changed to not the last one.
So had equal to case note the next.
OK.
And Ghaith, note turtlenecks equals to nuts.
Okay, now let's see and examine this method.
And let's go to here in the main.
And the start here exercise number five fifty five or fifty six fifty five
rotates rotate rotating list.
So linked list don't rotate link at least equal to one.
OK, then system that put in system the trend.
Or we can directly linked less to trends the list and we specify linked list the tab.
OK.
I will put here a message called After Repairs, after rotation, rotate that list.
Let's see rotated list.
It gives us for maybe there is some error.
Here.
There's a link, at least, OK, I would put.
And at the state, Lincoln, this.
And we specify here the known had indicated it had been.
Is.
OK.
I will bring the list.
Jack, I will call the method here Link at least take one, and then I will print the list.
Just print the list.
OK, so.
Naked list had let's run and see
that rotated list and smoking areas.
Let me check again if I meant this before.
This may be making some.
Troubles.
And here we go.
We have four, one, five and three.
I moved for.
I have moved for two here, and one becomes the head five, three and one.
I have rotated there, the list anti-clockwise.
OK, so this is how we can make a rotation for that link at last.
And by the way, we have finished all exercises with that are related to link atlas.
Maybe there are in the exams, all that or that section about the exercises, extra exercises and the
questions we are going to practice more and more.
But till now, we have created all of these methods and we have learned about iteration and recursively
and recursion.
And we have created at 99 percent of the methods or the questions and algorithms that are required for
your interview or your university.